Daniel French

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Details

College Station 832-316-7138 dan.r.french@sbcglobal.net

Links

Portfolio

Linkedin

GitHub

Codewars

Skills

C#

HTML5

CSS

GitHub

MySQL

ASP.NET

Microsoft Excel

Summary

I am a hardworking self-starter with a passion for learning, solving problems and analyzing information. I am proficient in C# and other programming languages that power some of the most useful and problem solving features on the web. I also have experience with integrating relational databases like MySQL with web applications.

Education

TrueCoders Full Stack Software Engineering Program, Birmingham

MAY 2023 - JUNE 2023

- Project-based training in programming languages and other technical skills, such as SQL, C#, .NET Core, Git, ASP.NET MVC, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- These skills were developed by building multiple C# and SQL projects in Visual Studio and Visual Studio Code
- C# and SQL Projects were tracked in Git and GitHub for source control
- Managed SQL databases using the CRUD operations in MySQL

Bachelor of Business Administration in Marketing, Texas A&M University-Kingsville, Kingsville

MAY 2005 - DECEMBER 2008

- Gained a solid foundation in marketing principles such as market research, consumer behavior and market segmentation
- Learned personal sales skills and techniques
- Learned strategies for market entry and analyzing strengths, weaknesses, opportunities, and threats in competitive markets
- Accounting Principles
- Graduated with honors (3.6 G.P.A.)

Experience

U.S. National Parks Directory Application

- ASP.NET Core MVC application built using C# and MySQL with Dapper and MySQL.Data NuGet Packages
- Database with tables for national parks and reviews built in MySQL
- Establishes an IDbConnection with MySQL database
- Exhibits CRUD functionality by allowing users to view information on parks and reviews, create new parks and reviews, update existing parks, and delete existing parks
 - Changes apply to application and database
- User interface designed using a combination of C#, JavaScript, CSS, and HTML
 - Sorting functionality added to parks and reviews pages
 - Rating system styled using Font Awesome

CSV Parsing and Geolocation TDD Project: C#

- Application made in Visual Studio using C#, .NET Core, and xUnit testing
- Uses a CSV document which lists the city and coordinates of different restaurants
- The application splits each line of the document into an array ([location name, latitude, longitude])
- Test-driven development ensures that invalid and missing data is handled correctly

- If the data is out of bounds or cannot be parsed, then the parse method returns null. Otherwise, the latitude and longitude are parsed
- The distance between each pair of coordinates is calculated to find the two restaurants furthest apart

Open Weather Map API Application

- Application made in Visual Studio using C#, ASP.NET Core, HTML, CSS and Newtonsoft. Json Nuget Package
- Calls an OpenWeatherMap.org API
- Parses through JSON objects to return the current weather for a given zip-code
- Displays the information in a .cshtml view page

Realtor, Keller Williams Realty Brazos Valley, College Station

APRIL 2021 - OCTOBER 2023

- Marketing our team's real estate services through social media, direct mail campaigns, and outbound phone calls
- Preparing and presenting pricing analyses and marketing strategies to prospective listing clients
- Showing properties to prospective buyers
- Maintaining transaction paperwork such as contract addenda, listing agreements, buyer's representation agreements, etc.
- Guiding clients through the process of buying/leasing or selling real estate

Courier, FedEx Express, College Station

JUNE 2014 - APRIL 2023

- Responsible for safely and efficiently sorting and delivering packages in College Station, TX and surrounding areas
- Led the team responsible for receiving and delivering First Overnight packages
- Supervised A.M. unloading activities and ensured a successful flow rate of packages per hour